<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>power on Guangchuang Yu</title>
    <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in power on Guangchuang Yu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 06:10:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guangchuangyu.github.io/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Five things biologists should know about statistics</title>
      <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2011/06/five-things-biologists-should-know-about-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 06:10:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2011/06/five-things-biologists-should-know-about-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebi.ac.uk/~birney/&#34;&gt;Ewan Birney&lt;/a&gt;最近的一篇博文（&lt;a href=&#34;http://genomeinformatician.blogspot.com/2011/06/five-statistical-things-i-wished-i-had.html&#34;&gt;Five statistical things I wished I had been taught 20 years ago&lt;/a&gt;
）讲述了统计对于生物学的重要性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一开始从RA Fisher讲起，说生物压根就是统计。Fisher是个农业学家，他所建立的那些统计方法，都是从生物学问题出发。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ewan所谈及的五个方面分别是：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Non parametric statistics. These are statistical tests which make a
bare minimum of assumptions of underlying distributions; in biology we
are rarely confident that we know the underlying distribution, and hand
waving about central limit theorem can only get you so far. Wherever
possible you should use a non parameteric test. This is Mann-Whitney (or
Wilcoxon if you prefer) for testing &amp;ldquo;medians&amp;rdquo; (Medians is in quotes
because this is not quite true. They test something which is closely
related to the median) of two distributions, Spearman&amp;rsquo;s Rho (rather
pearson&amp;rsquo;s r2) for correlation, and the Kruskal test rather than ANOVAs
(though if I get this right, you can&amp;rsquo;t in Kruskal do the more
sophisticated nested models you can do with ANOVA). Finally, don&amp;rsquo;t
forget the rather wonderful Kolmogorov-Smirnov (I always think it sounds
like really good vodka) test of whether two sets of observations come
from the same distribution. All of these methods have a basic theme of
doing things on the rank of items in a distribution, not the actual
level. So - if in doubt, do things on the rank of metric, rather than
the metric itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
