<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plagiarism on Guangchuang Yu</title>
    <link>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/tags/plagiarism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plagiarism on Guangchuang Yu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 13:22:22 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://guangchuangyu.github.io/tags/plagiarism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BMC Favor Plagiarism</title>
      <link>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2015/06/bmc-favor-plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 13:22:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2015/06/bmc-favor-plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ppiPre/index.html&#34;&gt;ppiPre&lt;/a&gt;抄袭了&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuangchuangYu/GOSemSim&#34;&gt;GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;的代码，证据当然非常充分，比对一下代码就知道了，我在&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/11/proper-use-of-gosemsim/&#34;&gt;Proper use of GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;一文中，做出了一些比较，另外也可以参考&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cran/ppiPre/commit/c267700ca09a599dab77326959a0aa6a2980ceed&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;页面，github记录了ppiPre被暴光抄袭之后所做的修改。
从我给BMC Systems
Biology的编辑反馈这件事开始，在这铁板钉钉的事实面前，编辑拖了整整一年，而这一年时间过去了，ppiPre仍没有被编辑部受理。从最早反应这件事情，编辑信誓旦旦说他们很重视这种事情，到后面对我的邮件视而不见，我愿意相信编辑部处理这些事情，需要时间，他们有自己的规则，但一年的时间，不回邮件，冷处理以淡化此事，这绝对不是应该有的规则。
在编辑一直无视我的情况下，我写出了&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/11/proper-use-of-gosemsim/&#34;&gt;Proper use of GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;一文，列举了一些一模一样的代码，并告知CRAN，当ppiPre被CRAN移除时，我写信给编辑，这时候，编辑告诉我说他们准备要去联系作者了，这时候已经过去半年了，是的！你没有看错，半年过去了，编辑说他们还没去联系作者！我是不相信的。必然是联系了之后，有某些不为人知的原因，所以编辑态度反常，对抄袭这种打鸡血的事情，不断在打太极。
再过二个月，ppiPre的作者&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.xidian.edu.cn/dengyue/&#34;&gt;邓岳&lt;/a&gt;给我写了信：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/master/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-06-08%2020.19.23.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
按照我在&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/11/proper-use-of-gosemsim/&#34;&gt;Proper use of GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;中说的:&amp;ldquo;你们可以抄我的代码，但要注明出处，引用我的文章&amp;rdquo;，进行了修改。我给他回信就是我可以接受这样的版本。事实上如果他们基于现在的版本发表文章，我没有任何问题。但现在的版本是迫于抄袭暴光所做出的修改，而发表文章时，抄代码不注出处，更改函数名，刻意回避我的文章，而且对抄袭部分在他们的文章中宣称是自己的实现，这是恶意抄袭。
回信说现在的版本OK之后，我觉得这会给出错误信息，于是我再写一封信，强调抄袭的严重性：
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/master/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-06-08%2020.18.52.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
从他的回信中，我感觉得出，态度并不好。他觉得只是对open
source的版权不够重视而已，这不单单是版权的问题，还是出版伦理（publication
ethics）的问题，再怎么对版权无知，你不能发表文章说别人做的东西是你做的。
事实上邓岳并没有意识到问题，2015年继续发表抄袭的R包&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4321842/&#34;&gt;HPOSim&lt;/a&gt;，这个包的代码抄袭了哈医大李霞实验室的&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biomedcentral.com/1471-2105/12/266&#34;&gt;DOSim&lt;/a&gt;，而DOSim又是抄了&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/GOSim.html&#34;&gt;GOSim&lt;/a&gt;，我手贱对比了一下代码，竟然发现抄袭链条，而且抄袭者都发了文章，但发完文章，相应的包也就被CRAN移除了，要么是不维护，要么是主动要求移除。这个圈子好乱有木有！
我也没必要去跟他掐，而是等待编辑的处理，我期望编辑给他上一课，做科研没有这样的捷径。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;最终编辑给出的邮件是：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Guangchuang,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back through my emails, I did receive a response back from the authors previously. They in turn said that the email address I had originally been trying to contact them with earlier last year was no longer in use, so they only received my emails when I found an additional alternative email address for the authors in my more recent emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their explanation for the use of your code was that as the similarity measures were not their main focus of their study they had intended to either implement existing methods themselves or as in the case of GoSemSim, import the packages. However they had some problems with this and instead utilised the source code directly. Their rationale was that as the code was GPL licenced that this was acceptable, without realising that it was also required to cite the original source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say they have now created an updated version which they say has the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) ppiPre imports GOSemSim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) ppiPre calls function geneSim() exported by GOSemSim to calculate Wang’s measure, instead of deriving code from GOSemSim directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) Several internal functions of ppiPre (TCSSGetAncestors, GetOntology, GetGOParents, GetLatestCommonAncestor, TCSSCompute_ICA) are derived from GOSemSim since GOSemSim don’t export them. In source code (.R) and manuals (.RD), acknowledgement has been added including the information of author and publication of GOSemSim.
(4) The author of GOSemSim (Guangchuang Yu) has been added in the ‘Author’ filed as contributor, as required by CRAN Repository Policy.
(5) All the information content data in data directory of ppiPre have been removed. ppiPre directly obtained data from GOSemSim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version has been available in SourceForge (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/p/ppipre/&#34;&gt;https://sourceforge.net/p/ppipre/&lt;/a&gt;). And we are submitting ppiPre to CRAN. We will notify you after ppiPre is available on CRAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also apologise for failing to cite you correctly and have asked if they may submit a correction to their article to rectify this. This would be within our policy if this sounds acceptable to you. Please let me know if you would need more details or if you need to get in touch with the authors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,
Tim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;列举的几点跟邓岳给我的中文信一样，但多了两点： 1.
强调这是由于对版权的无知。 2. 抄袭的，不是文章的重点。
1是给自己找个借口，犯错是因为无知。2则淡化的抄袭的严重性。完全没有认错的意思。我们完全可以想像，所谓的“they
may submit a correction to their article to rectify
this”是什么样子的。所以我不能接受。
如果是真心认错，不遮遮掩掩，大胆地接受所犯的错误，那么发表声明，对此事进行道歉，我可以接受。
但在作者没有认错的情况下，在编辑最后明显倾向性的言语中，我无法接受，无知是对版权，你做科研，能发paper说别人的东西是自己的？总不能这样无知吧？代码2/3是抄GOSemSim的，并且文章中大篇幅在说实现了这些算法，还能睁眼说瞎话，说不是重点，就差说出来not
a big deal了。
我坚决不能同意，于是回信给了编辑，然而编辑又再次遁了！一年以来，不是我不断给编辑压力，编辑根本就无视我，而最后到了该给个说法的时候了，又继续玩消失。要说没有内幕，有人相信么？我反正是不信。
对于抄袭，这是铁的事实，开源和版权，不是重点，这本身是严重的出版伦理问题。而这一整年编辑的表现，又使这一事情，呈现出更严重的一面，编辑一直在袒护抄袭者，这是非常反常的，编辑对这种事情，一直应该是打鸡血的，他们善于站在道德的制高点，对科研工作者指手画脚，而BMC也一直以此宣传他们，像今年撤了四十多篇中国的文章，说是manipulating
review process，这种事情大家也是非常支持的，再怎么想文章，不能走偏门。
正如&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/&#34;&gt;Andrew
Gelman&lt;/a&gt;在评论ppiPre抄袭这件事时说的：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we’re talking about people who already are skating on the ethical edge (as scientists, we should always respond to serious criticism; if we don’t, that’s bordering on ethical violation already)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;做为科研工作者，我们已经在道德的边缘上如履薄冰，对严重批评不做出回应，则已然是违反道德。
BMC现在就是在做违反道德的事情，非常反常！这可能是比&amp;rsquo;manipulating review
process&amp;rsquo; 更严重的mainipulating editorial
board。我知道掐这事于我没有任何好处，还会得罪很多人，但科研的正义必须维护，抄袭的行为必须打击，编辑部腐败更不能容忍！这件事情必须得有个说法。
ppiPre是发表在&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aporc.org/ISB/2012/&#34;&gt;ISB
2012&lt;/a&gt;会议上的，这个会议明显是和BMC
Systems Biology合作的，会议文章发表在BMC Systems
Biology专刊上，而ppiPre的通讯作者&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.xidian.edu.cn/lgao/&#34;&gt;高琳&lt;/a&gt;是会议的Program
Chairs，而某些BMC Systems Biology的编委是General
Chairs，通讯作者和BMC编委是认识的，于是我空穴来风地猜测了一下，某些编委不顾道德伦理在袒护ppiPre的抄袭行为。事情真相到底是什么，期待BMC最终能给个说法。如果抄袭都能不撤稿，如果编委都能被操控，我们有什么理由相信科研！还不如趁早转工业界去赚点养家糊口的钱。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BMC favors source code plagiarism</title>
      <link>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2015/05/bmc-favors-source-code-plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 13:38:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2015/05/bmc-favors-source-code-plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found source code plagiarism a year ago and reported this case to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biomedcentral.com/bmcsystbiol&#34;&gt;BMC Systems Biology&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/0f22f6ad87427adb59941160130b016ee1e41004/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-05-27%2019.56.58.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listed source code of many functions that are exactly copied from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/GOSemSim.html&#34;&gt;GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;
with only function name changed in my email. The detail of source code
plagiarism can also be found at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/11/proper-use-of-gosemsim/&#34;&gt;Proper use of
GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got reply from the Editor 3 days after (see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/0f22f6ad87427adb59941160130b016ee1e41004/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-05-27%2019.58.16.png&#34;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MS: 1069569029107167
Research
ppiPre: predicting protein-protein interactions by combining heterogeneous features
BMC Systems Biology 2013, 7:S8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Dr Yu,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your message and bringing this to our attention. Firstly I would like to assure you that we do take cases of plagiarism very seriously. We are members of the Committee on Publication Ethics (&lt;a href=&#34;http://publicationethics.org&#34;&gt;http://publicationethics.org&lt;/a&gt;) follow their guidelines for circumstances such as this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first step we will be investigating the overlap between this publication in BMC Systems Biology and your previously published work, to establish the extent of the duplication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could I just check, have you compared all the code in the ppiPRE article for similarity with your own code? That is, is there any possibility that more of your code has been duplicated without attribution? We will of course have to examine the code for unattributed use of other authors code in addition to your own&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do let us know if there are more relevant details you are aware of. We will be in contact again in due course as our investigations proceed, but do not hesitate to contact me in the meantime if you would like an update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,
Tim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The editor assured me that they &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;do take cases of plagiarism very
seriously&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo; and will investigate the overlap. I was waiting for their
update. But 5 months passed, I never receive any reply from them even I
sent several emails to ask for updates. I have no idea how long their
&amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;due course&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo; is. As I did not receive any reply, I wrote a blog post
(see &lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/11/proper-use-of-gosemsim/&#34;&gt;Proper use of
GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;) to bring
this to the R community and CRAN did remove the ppiPre package at that
time. I told the Editor that this package had been removed from CRAN and
again asked for update. This time, he did reply me (see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/master/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-05-27%2020.11.54.png&#34;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MS: 1069569029107167
Research
ppiPre: predicting protein-protein interactions by combining heterogeneous features
BMC Systems Biology 2013, 7:S8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Guangchuang,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your message and my apologies for the delay in this investigation. We had been trying to identify if any other code had also been plagiarised in the publication, although we did not find any evidence of this. Thank you also for drawing our attention to the removal of ppiPre from CRAN. We will be in touch with the article authors and will let you know when there is a further update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,
Tim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can find in the editor&amp;rsquo;s email, &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;We will be in touch with the
article authors&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;, they never contact the authors after 5 months passed
from my report. In the following 2 months, I never receive any reply
again. I was angry and sent an email to several Editors of BMC to
complain that they are ruinning the reputation of BMC. Then again as
expected, I got email (see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/master/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-05-27%2020.33.30.png&#34;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Guangchuang,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are continuing to pursue this case. As you will understand, as well as the clear evidence of plagiarism of your code, we are concerned about possible unacknowledged reuse of other code as well. We have been trying to contact the authors for a full explanation, as this will affect how we can address the issue. Until very recently we had not been successful in contacting them, although they have very recently got back to us  and have said that they are considering their response, so we expect an update soon. From our perspective it is highly preferable for the authors to come clean about the issues and for any correction or retraction notice to come from them rather than from the editors, and for this reason it is often a drawn out process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your patience, and I can again assure you that this will be addressed formally in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely,
Tim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to see this as the editor told me they have contacted
the authors and will have an update soon. I wait another 3 months
without any update as usual. I asked for update again and this time they
did give me an update (see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/master/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-04-23%2021.31.55.png&#34;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Guangchuang,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back through my emails, I did receive a response back from the authors previously. They in turn said that the email address I had originally been trying to contact them with earlier last year was no longer in use, so they only received my emails when I found an additional alternative email address for the authors in my more recent emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their explanation for the use of your code was that as the similarity measures were not their main focus of their study they had intended to either implement existing methods themselves or as in the case of GoSemSim, import the packages. However they had some problems with this and instead utilised the source code directly. Their rationale was that as the code was GPL licenced that this was acceptable, without realising that it was also required to cite the original source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say they have now created an updated version which they say has the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) ppiPre imports GOSemSim.
(2) ppiPre calls function geneSim() exported by GOSemSim to calculate Wang’s measure, instead of deriving code from GOSemSim directly.
(3) Several internal functions of ppiPre (TCSSGetAncestors, GetOntology, GetGOParents, GetLatestCommonAncestor, TCSSCompute_ICA) are derived from GOSemSim since GOSemSim don’t export them. In source code (.R) and manuals (.RD), acknowledgement has been added including the information of author and publication of GOSemSim.
(4) The author of GOSemSim (Guangchuang Yu) has been added in the ‘Author’ filed as contributor, as required by CRAN Repository Policy.
(5) All the information content data in \data directory of ppiPre have been removed. ppiPre directly obtained data from GOSemSim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version has been available in SourceForge (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/p/ppipre/&#34;&gt;https://sourceforge.net/p/ppipre/&lt;/a&gt;). And we are submitting ppiPre to CRAN. We will notify you after ppiPre is available on CRAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also apologise for failing to cite you correctly and have asked if they may submit a correction to their article to rectify this. This would be within our policy if this sounds acceptable to you. Please let me know if you would need more details or if you need to get in touch with the authors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,
Tim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the changes, ppiPre is back to CRAN. Now in CRAN, what we can find
is that ppiPre use source code from GOSemSim properly with
acknowledgement. They removed all previous source tarball so that their
source code plagiarism was gone. Fortunately, github recorded all the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cran/ppiPre/commit/c267700ca09a599dab77326959a0aa6a2980ceed&#34;&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt;.
The editor delay the processing to give the authors enough time to
remove their bad records. I think CRAN shouldn&amp;rsquo;t accept re-submitted
package if it was removed for plagiarism issue. In the email, the editor
not only conveyed explanation from the author, but also have expressed
their opinion: &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;They also apologise for failing to cite you correctly
and have asked if they may submit a correction to their article to
rectify this. This would be within our policy if this sounds acceptable
to you&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;. This is why I think BMC do favor source code plagiarism.
Their judgement/opinion is not fair! I can&amp;rsquo;t accept their explanation
and replied to the editor (see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuangchuangYu/ygc_name/master/2015/plagiarism/Screenshot%202015-04-23%2021.45.33.png&#34;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Prof. Sands,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your email. That makes it more clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t accept their explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ppiPre is a die package, they didn&amp;rsquo;t update any source code or IC data after publication, with the fact that annotation packages for calculating IC data have updated several times. The recent changes were forced by my report of plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent update follows the requirement of GPL license which requires the derivative work also GPL licensed and acknowledge original works. That&amp;rsquo;s good, but remember it was forced to happen after my report of source code plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the version they published the paper, it is indeed source codes copied without any acknowledgement and the proportion is very large (about &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of ppiPre was copied from GOSemSim).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their explanation, the author claimed that similarity measures were not their main focus. Can I ask what&amp;rsquo;s their main focus? SVM for protein-pretein interaction prediction as indicated in the title of the paper and in the package name? The SVM in that package is less than 80 lines, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cran/ppiPre/blob/master/R/SVMPredict.r&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cran/ppiPre/blob/master/R/SVMPredict.r&lt;/a&gt; with more than half in calling similarity measures, and several empty lines, paramter checking and preparing input and output. They did nothing in svm; they just call e1071::svm in line 28 and and e1071::predict in line 16 with default parameters (users even don&amp;rsquo;t have chance to change kernel function in their package). If that&amp;rsquo;s their main focus, what&amp;rsquo;s their contribution of their paper? In the Method session, their only use a small paragraph, Prediction framework, that only mention they used svm for prediction but with many paragraphs emphasizing they have implemented many GO semantic similarity measures. They call svm implemented in e1071 package to train features calculated by source codes from GOSemSim. How do they explain this?  I do have no idea of their so call main focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also mentioned that they had problems in importing GOSemSim. This is also un-acceptable. As they copied most of the functions without any change, it is easy to import these functions using GOSemSim:::un-exported_function if the function is not exported. If they don&amp;rsquo;t know this feature and did not google search how to do it. They should contact me for help or ask for my permission of re-using my codes. But they didn&amp;rsquo;t. They may believe they can use my source code freely as it is GPL licensed, they should know that open source license also have requirement of acknowledgement. Even that&amp;rsquo;s due to their ignorance, why they only change the function names to pretend that&amp;rsquo;s their own functions? If these are not their main focus, why more than half of the text in the paper explaining the calculation of these algorithms and claim they were implemented in their package?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they are not intended to do this, they will have acknowledgement in their source code, they will have citation in their paper and they will not just change function name that was copied without other changes. They intended to do so to cheat editor, reviewers and readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) ppiPre calls function geneSim() exported by GOSemSim to calculate Wang’s measure, instead of deriving code from GOSemSim directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, most of the source code is not &amp;lsquo;derived&amp;rsquo; but copied from GOSemSim with only function name changed which can still be detected in the updated version, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cran/ppiPre/blob/master/R/GOKEGGSims.r&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cran/ppiPre/blob/master/R/GOKEGGSims.r&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,
Guangchuang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND again, the editor just ignore my email!&lt;/strong&gt; 1 year passed and the
case is very clear that they copied my source code and intended to
pretend that&amp;rsquo;s their original work and use it to publish a paper. That&amp;rsquo;s
definitely plagiarism. The editor replied me very quickly at the
beginning and assured me that BMC do take cases like this seriously. I
don&amp;rsquo;t know what happened after they contacted the authors. The editor
always ignore my email except I put some pressure to them, they delay
the process and try to persuade me that this is due to the author&amp;rsquo;s
ignorance of open source license and an apology from the author is
enough to solve this issue. If you see this post, you are welcome to
comment and please help share it to social media. This will helps to
give BMC some pressure and I will contact COPE if they won&amp;rsquo;t addressing
this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>