<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proteomics on Guangchuang YU</title>
    <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/categories/proteomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proteomics on Guangchuang YU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Guangchuang YU</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 10:57:15 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/proteomics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>using GOSemSim to rank proteins obtained by co-IP</title>
      <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2015/05/using-gosemsim-to-rank-proteins-obtained-by-co-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 10:57:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2015/05/using-gosemsim-to-rank-proteins-obtained-by-co-ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-IP is usually used to identified interactions among specific
proteins. It is widely used in detecting protein complex. Unfortunately,
an identified protein may not be an interactor, and sometimes can be a
background contaminant. Ranking proteins can help us to focus a study on
a few high quality candidates for subsequent interaction investigation.
My R package &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuangchuangYu/GOSemSim&#34;&gt;GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt; has
been used in many studies to investigate protein protein interaction,
see &lt;a href=&#34;http://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlehtml/2014/mb/c3mb70486f&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1874391915000937&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1476927115000493&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcponline.org/content/13/5/1318.short&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.com/scholar?oi=bibs&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;cites=9484177541993722322,16048119560581430155,18126401808149291947&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the study, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1874391912007567&#34;&gt;Proteomic investigation of the interactome of FMNL1 in hematopoietic cells unveils a role in calcium-dependent membrane plasticity&lt;/a&gt;,
we investigate the interactors of FMNL1 by co-IP followed by LC-MS/MS
analysis. In this study, we defined functional similarity as the
geometric mean of semantic similarities in molecular function and
cellular component. Functional similarity is designed for measuring the
strength of the relationship between each protein and its partners by
considering function and location of proteins. The similarities were
calculated through &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuangchuangYu/GOSemSim&#34;&gt;GOSemSim&lt;/a&gt;
package. The distributions of the functional similarities were
demonstrated in the following figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/blog_images/2015/Screen-Shot-2014-12-16-at-12.05.58-am.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the average functional similarities between the protein and its
interaction partners to rank the protein. Proteins, which have strong
relationship in function and location among the proteins within the
interactome, were essential for the interactome to exert their
functions. AHNAK1 has strong spatial and temporal interaction with other
proteins and was selected for functional study. AHNAK1 had not been
identified as an interaction partner of FMNL1, and we confirmed that it
interacts at its C-terminus with N-terminal region of FMNL1. Previous
study had reported AHNAK1 is calcium-dependent, and our study found that
FMNL1 enhances ionophore-mediated calcium influx by inducing
translocation of AHNAK1. This point to a new function of FMNL1 as a
modulator in calcium-dependent cytoskeletal membrane processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yu G&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;, Li F&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;, Qin Y, Bo X&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;, Wu Y and Wang S&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/content/26/7/976&#34;&gt;GOSemSim: an R package for measuring semantic similarity among GO terms and gene products&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. 2010, 26(7):976-978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://d1bxh8uas1mnw7.cloudfront.net/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;altmetric-embed&#34; data-badge-popover=&#34;right&#34; data-badge-type=&#34;donut&#34; data-altmetric-id=&#34;100979&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
