<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Osx on Guangchuang YU</title>
    <link>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/tags/osx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Osx on Guangchuang YU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Guangchuang YU</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 13:40:22 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://guangchuangyu.github.io/tags/osx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>yet an unofficial BioEdit for OSX</title>
      <link>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/post/software/2016_bioedit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 13:40:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/post/software/2016_bioedit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mbio.ncsu.edu/bioedit/bioedit.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mbio.ncsu.edu/bioedit/Banner1.GIF&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mbio.ncsu.edu/bioedit/bioedit.html&#34;&gt;BioEdit&lt;/a&gt; is the most comprehensive biological sequence alignment editor. Most of my labmates run this software using &lt;code&gt;Parallels Desktop&lt;/code&gt;. For some of them, BioEdit is the only reason to install &lt;code&gt;Parallels Desktop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to edit my alignment recently, and install it in my iMac using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/&#34;&gt;Wine&lt;/a&gt;, which is a compatibility layer for running Windows applications on POSIX-compliant OS. Although it is famous in Linux community for many years, many OSX users never heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came out with an idea that maybe I can pack all the components into an OSX application bundle. Then I can share it with my labmates and others. I don&amp;rsquo;t need to teach them how to install and config &lt;code&gt;Wine&lt;/code&gt; and they can just drag the App to &lt;code&gt;/Applications&lt;/code&gt; and double click to run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me one night to create this App. You can click &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/GuangchuangYu/BioEdit-OSX/raw/master/BioEdit.dmg&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to download it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, you can install it by dragging the App to &lt;code&gt;Applications&lt;/code&gt; folder and open it by double click. It works just like native App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/blog_images/2016/Screenshot 2016-03-30 11.30.03.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW: If you don&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;a href=&#34;http://xquartz.macosforge.org/&#34;&gt;XQuartz&lt;/a&gt; installed, you need one for running &lt;code&gt;BioEdit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello yosemite</title>
      <link>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/post/mac/2014_hello-yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 04:34:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guangchuangyu.github.io/post/mac/2014_hello-yosemite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/blog_images/2014/11/Screenshot-2014-11-11-14.07.45.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing OS is painful, you need to re-install all the software and
configure them to the way you want. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to wast time in doing
this. To prevent doing this dirty job, we perform an upgrade install
instead of clean install. We all have experience of upgrading Windows
sucks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://osxdaily.com/2014/10/17/os-x-yosemite-installation-stuck/&#34;&gt;same as OS X&lt;/a&gt;.
All the issues you have in old system will be remained, and sometimes
new issues will be introduced in the process of upgrading. The system
will be slower compare to clean install one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is short, we want a clean system without wasting time in setting
software, but how can it be. The answer is yes and no. Firstly, you
should have two partitions, one for OS and the other one for your data.
Only in this way, you can formatting the system partition and keep your
data untouch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was an undergraduate student, I install both
&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/categories/bsd&#34;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/categories/linux&#34;&gt;debian&lt;/a&gt; in my PC. They were configured to
share the same home partition, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to configure
software in both of the systems. In OS X, the home directory is not
located at traditional path /home/userName, but at /Users/userName. You
should change your home directory from system partition to your data
partition. If you have done that, you can formatting your system
partition as I do and clean install the OS X system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the system was installed, I need to install Xcode for compiling
software, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tug.org/mactex/&#34;&gt;MacTex&lt;/a&gt; for compiling $\LaTeX$
documents, and MS office, which is the reason I need &lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2012/03/installing-hackintosh/&#34;&gt;OS X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all the other software I used in OS X is the same as in Linux.
After I setting the home directory to my previous location. All the
software will perform as in my old system. My setting of the trackpad is
remain, and so as my dock items; Firefox have its bookmarks and plugins;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://guangchuangyu.github.io/2013/09/install-emacs-on-mac/&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; know how to
load extensions; Even plugins I installed for MS Word are already there.
I don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything, and everything works in their old way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upgrading R is tedious, for you need to re-install all the packages. The
library path for brew installed R is something like this:
&amp;lsquo;﻿﻿/usr/local/Cellar/r/3.1.2/R.framework/Versions/3.1/Resources/library&amp;rsquo;.
If you installed your packages in this folder, you need to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r-bloggers.com/update-all-user-installed-r-packages-again/&#34;&gt;get installed package names&lt;/a&gt; from it. The path is long and hard to remember (many soft links may get you lost if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the function &amp;lsquo;.libPaths()&amp;rsquo;). My solution is
to install all my packages in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/R/3.1/library&lt;/code&gt;, so after I re-installed R, all the packages are still there. When R is upgrade to 3.2, all I need is to move the folder from 3.1 to 3.2 and use one command &amp;lsquo;update.packages(ask=FALSE, checkBuilt=TRUE)&amp;rsquo; to update them. This is a painless way for R and this idea is the secret of painless clean install of UNIX-like systems including OS X.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>