<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Guangchuang YU</title>
    <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Guangchuang YU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Guangchuang YU</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 13:40:22 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guangchuangyu.github.io/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>yet an unofficial BioEdit for OSX</title>
      <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2016/03/yet-an-unofficial-bioedit-for-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 13:40:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2016/03/yet-an-unofficial-bioedit-for-osx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mbio.ncsu.edu/bioedit/bioedit.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mbio.ncsu.edu/bioedit/Banner1.GIF&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my knowledge, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mbio.ncsu.edu/bioedit/bioedit.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BioEdit&lt;/a&gt; is the most comprehensive biological sequence alignment editor. Most of my labmates run this software using &lt;code&gt;Parallels Desktop&lt;/code&gt;. For some of them, BioEdit is the only reason to install &lt;code&gt;Parallels Desktop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to edit my alignment recently, and install it in my iMac using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wine&lt;/a&gt;, which is a compatibility layer for running Windows applications on POSIX-compliant OS. Although it is famous in Linux community for many years, many OSX users never heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>auto-complete in ESS</title>
      <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/12/auto-complete-in-ess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 10:22:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/12/auto-complete-in-ess/</guid>
      <description>Auto complete is good, it can save you times in typing and prevent typo sometimes.
RStudio now supports function arguments in auto complete. ESS&amp;rsquo;s auto complete is more advance, it supports help page.
We should use &amp;lsquo;ess-use-auto-complete&amp;rsquo; to activate auto complete in ESS buffers.
(setq ess-use-auto-complete t)  The effect is quite amazing. Auto-complete extension is needed for ESS, we need to install the auto-complete extension and load it at Emacs startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>install 454 GS Data Analysis Software on ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/09/install-454-gs-data-analysis-software-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 15:38:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2014/09/install-454-gs-data-analysis-software-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Usually Roche&amp;rsquo;s installer is a catastrophe, they only provides rpm packages of the software for 454 GS FLX (version 2.9). Although the package contains setup.sh, the script is useless since it is actually a binary payload.
I run the setup.sh, and it throw error of not finding /sbin/lspci. In debian derived distribution, lspci command is located in /bin folder. This issue is easy to solve by adding a soft link to /sbin/lspci.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>local blast</title>
      <link>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2013/11/local-blast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 10:40:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guangchuangyu.github.io/2013/11/local-blast/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to set up a local blast for the lab. Blast can be installed directly using apt in debian and it turns out to be easy.
root@jz:/ssd/genomes# apt-get install ncbi-blast+ Reading package lists... Done Building dependency tree Reading state information... Done The following NEW packages will be installed: ncbi-blast+ 0 upgraded, 1 newly installed, 0 to remove and 26 not upgraded. Need to get 11.2 MB of archives. After this operation, 32.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>